safehome.org 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy - SafeHome.org

Last Updated: July 5, 2018

 **  Our Commitment to Privacy.** This notice describes the Privacy Policy for SafeHome.org (“Website”). Our Privacy Policy is designed to advise you about how we collect, use, disclose, share, and protect your personal information and personal data. By visiting this site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is effective immediately for users who visit the Website on or after the date set forth above. By using our Website, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

 **What Information is Collected.**

Information You Provide to Us: We collect any information you enter on our Website, or that you give us in any other way including your full name, email address, zip code, physical address, and other information you may provide such as your gender, phone number, or birth date. When you communicate with us (via email, phone, through the Website, or any other way), we may maintain a record of the communication. You can choose not to provide certain information, but you may not be able to take full advantage of our services and features.

Automatic Information and Log Files: When you visit our Website, you and your computer or mobile device may disclose certain browsing information to us in connection with your use of our Website and services. The information may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, type of browser, Internet Service Provider, the date and time of your visit, requesting/referring/exit pages and URLs, search activity, number of clicks, type of computer or mobile device, WiFi information such as SSID, mobile carrier, phone number, unique device identifier, advertising identifier, and location (including geolocation, beacon based location, and GPS location). This Website, like many other websites, records this information about visits to our Website.

“Cookies” and Web Beacons: Cookies are pieces of information that are transferred to your computer from a web server. Most browsers are set up to accept cookies, but you can change your settings to have your browser notify you when you receive a new cookie or to refuse to accept cookies. Cookies may transmit information about you and your use of the Website and our services, and may be persistent or stored only during an individual session. Web beacons are images placed on a website to monitor the use of its content. We, and third parties with whom we partner, may use cookies, web beacons, tags, scripts, advertising identifiers, local shared objects such as HTML5 and Flash and similar technology in connection with your use of the Website. Some of the purposes for which cookies and web beacons are used are to ensure the functionality of our Website’s processes, for authentication, security and compliance, to optimize user preferences, and for notifications, advertising and security.

 **Cookies Declaration**

 **How and When the Information is Used.**  The information we collect is used for administering our business activities, improving user experience, providing users with continued access to relevant information, products, and services, analyzing trends, displaying relevant advertising, marketing the home security systems listed on our Website, gathering demographic information, tracking movement on the Website, allowing for disaster recovery, enhancing the security of our Website and services, and complying with legal obligations. We may use the information to record visitor preferences, user-specific information, pages the user accesses or visits, and to customize content for particular users. Occasionally we may also use the information collected to notify you about changes to our Website, new services, or special offers. If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the website for each respective web browser.

If you request information regarding a home security system or anything related home security through our Website, we may send you messages or contact you about your request using the contact information you provide to us or make publicly available, or that we have on record for you, including through telephone and our auto-dial telephone system, email, and automated SMS text messages to your phone number.

 **How We Protect Your Information.**  The privacy and protection of your information is important to us. We use various safeguards to protect the personal information that you submit to us.

 **Methods We Use to Protect Your Information.  **We use security software to protect the confidentiality of your personal information. In addition, our business practices are reviewed periodically for compliance with policies and procedures governing the security and confidentiality of the information we store. Our business practices limit employee access to confidential information and limit the use and disclosure of such information to authorized persons. This Website does not provide services or sell products to children under the age of 18. If you are under 18, you may use this Website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian. Unfortunately, no method of electronic transmission or storage of information over the internet or via mobile device is completely secure. Although we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information, we make every commercially reasonable effort to protect our users’ personal information.

 **Who Has Access to Your Information.**  Information about our users is important to us. Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy or to comply with applicable law, we will not disclose any personal information to a third party without first receiving a user’s consent which users give through the use of our Website. Some of the ways third parties may receive information about you are as follows.

 **Advertisers.** Some of our third party advertisers may also use the information collected, or collect additional personal information about an individual user’s online activities on our Website, to measure the effectiveness of advertisements and to personalize advertising content that you see. Our Website may have no access to or control over the cookies used by third party advertisers. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third party advertisers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control, the activities of third party advertisers advertising on our Website.

 **Third Party Service Providers.** Third parties may provide support to our Website or other services in connection with your use of our Website and the services we offer on our Website. We may share information with these third parties to enable them to perform their services. These third parties may also share information with us that they obtain from or about you in connection with providing their services to our Website, and they may also share this information with their affiliates.

 **Aggregate or Anonymous Information.** We may share with third parties information about our users in the aggregate, or anonymous user information.

 **Business Sale or Transfers.** We may share information about users with our affiliated companies, subsidiaries, parent companies, joint ventures, or other businesses under common control and with another company that acquires us or all or substantially all of our assets, in which case we will require such other companies to honor this Privacy Policy.

 **Home Security Systems.** We may share information about users with providers of home security systems listed or not listed on our Website.

 **Legal Compliance.** We may also share information about users to comply with legal obligations or legal processes, or pursuant to court order or law enforcement instruction.

 **How You Can Access Your Information.**  You can request access to all your personal information by contacting our Data Privacy Representative as set forth below.

 **Contact.** You may contact our Data Privacy Representative at [info@safehome.org](mailto:info@safehome.org).

 **Changes to Privacy Policy.**  If our Privacy Policy or procedures change, we will immediately post those changes to our Website. Any such changes will be effective immediately upon being posted, unless otherwise stated in the change.
